Hello everyone, we are very happy to be able to launch a new integrated function in CLO 2026.0 update.
Previously, you had to use sewing lines or fake sewing to fix pockets and decals.
Now, using the integrated tool, you can apply glue to the entire board or a specific area to make the two boards perfectly integrated.
The integrated function is designed to support a seamless structure.
Next, let's take a look at how these functions work in the actual workflow.
The first function I will demonstrate is the fill-in-integration tool.
Select the fill-in-integration tool from the 2D tool bar.
The tool can automatically identify the border or internal shape of the board and quickly define the integrated area.
First, you need to ensure that the internal shape on the basic board is the same as that of the integrated purple board.
Then, place the purple board accurately on the upper part of the basic board.
Click on the purple board.
After clicking on the purple board, the board will be displayed in orange color.
This shows that the integrated connection has been established.
After the integration, you can move the board at will.
The integrated state will remain unchanged.
This tool works the same way in the 3D window.
Place the purple board close to the front or back of the basic board.
At this time, the purple board in the 2D window does not need to overlap with the basic board.
Use the fill-in-integration tool to click on the purple board to set the integration.
When the tool is activated, you will see the fill-in-integration option window in the upper right corner of the 3D window.
If you change the mode to subtract and click on the integrated board, the integration will be removed.
For this kind of gray bar, we can also use the quick integration tool.
It allows you to paste a board into the exact position you want.
Select the quick integration tool in the 2D tool bar.
Click on the board you want to integrate.
A gray bar with the outline of a board will move along your mouse cursor.
Use this guide to determine the integration position on the basic board and then click again.
The biggest advantage of the quick integration tool is that you don't have to manually overlap the board in the 2D window in advance.
The gray bar can help you specify the entire integration area immediately.
Next, I will explain how to cancel the quick integration.
You need to switch to the fill-in-integration tool first.
In the mode of fill-in-integration window, select subtract.
Click on the integrated board to cancel.
After opening the simulation, you can see that the board has been removed from the large board.
Use the quick integration tool to re-integrate this board.
Finally, let's take a look at the pen and brush integration tool.
Replace the purple board to the basic board.
In the 2D tool bar, click and hold the integration tool for 2 seconds.
Then select the pen and brush integration from the purple menu.
Unlike the pen and brush integration for the entire board or the internal shape integration,
using the pen and brush integration can freely specify the integration area on the board.
When the two boards are re-integrated,
you only need to drag the area you want to re-integrate to apply.
The orange color will appear on the screen.
When you run the simulation, you will see the purple board.
Perfectly along the area of the orange color,
re-integrate on the basic board.
Let's take a look at the setting of the pen and brush integration in the upper right corner.
There are two types of types.
The outer is the type just displayed.
It is the reverse of the glue applied to the purple board,
making it re-integrated to the outer of the basic board.
This type is used in most cases.
On the integration of the board to the board,
the inner side is the surface of the glue applied to the basic board,
making it re-integrated to the inner side of the purple board.
In short, although the position of the glue is different,
the result is the same.
The two boards are firmly re-integrated into one whole.
Change between increase or decrease mode
to create a new re-integration area or remove some existing areas.
Adjust the pen and brush size to adapt to your board.
You can drag and slide or enter a specific value
to apply fine details or enlarge the area.
According to your work process,
the 2D window or 3D window
may be different in different cases.
The 2D window is most suitable for
completely matching the shape of the two boards,
or when the structure of the layer is simple,
it will be faster and more convenient to use.
The 3D window is most suitable for
different shapes of boards,
or you need to place the board accurately
and use it in the complex curved structure of the simulation.
Please consider the shape and structure of your board
to choose the window that is most suitable for the situation.
This function is widely used not only for clothing,
but also for painting.
It is also used for other types of products,
such as shoes, hats, etc.
Try to use the integrated function
to paste the sticker label or the wireless pocket.
You will be able to create the layer effect of the pen
more quickly and more easily.
We hope you can explore in various design projects
and enjoy the fun of using these new tools.